Tom Martin

tpgmartin@gmail.com

+44(0)7946 330544

linkedin.com/in/tpgmartin medium.com/@tpgmartin

tpgmartin.com

github.com/tpgmartin

Profile

Data scientist with previous commercial experience as a software engineer in companies ranging from startups to large e-commerce companies. Able to bring together experience from both fields to deliver impactful business solutions. Use Python and libraries such as Pandas, NumPy as well as Tableau, Airflow, AWS, and NoSQL technologies.

Skills

Programming Languages Python, JavaScript, Node.js, R, Ruby

Libraries Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, JupyterLab, SciPy, PySpark, TensorFlow

Data Visualisation Metabase, Tableau, Google Data Studio

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon Redshift

Infrastructure AWS, GCP, Microsoft Azure, Docker

Experience

Customer Analytics Data Scientist, Senior Associate

PwC, London, UK

Feb 2021 (current)

Consultant Data Scientist

CybSafe, London, UK

- Scoped and outlined data components of major B2B product, performing all data science work independently
- Development of novel model to predict time between user email prompts
- Consultation and development of KPIs, metrics, and dashboarding for multiple initiatives
- Multiple company-wide presentations
- Ongoing support for data platform and MLOps

Data Scientist Apr - Oct 2019

Capita Employee Solutions, London, UK

- Created probabilistic models for major public sector project
- Curated data sources and produced multiple data components for B2B

Nov 2019 - Oct 2020

product

- Created self-service Flask web app deployed on Microsoft Azure

Data Scientist Nov 2017 - Mar 2019

Skills Matter, London, UK

- Created web app to view conference reviews using ranking algorithm and sentiment analysis
- Customer segmentation and analysis
- Created and maintained data infrastructure
- Mentored junior members of staff on data analysis tools

Software Engineer Dec 2014 - Nov 2017

OpenTable, London, UK

- Full-stack web developer
- Developed microservices, using full-stack JavaScript: NodeJS, Express, Hapi, Backbone, React, Grunt, MongoDB, Webpack
- DevOps culture: Docker, Mesos, Singularity

Developer May - Oct 2014

Modaventure, London, UK

Public Speaking

- The Why of Data-Driven Organisations, Infiniteconf 2018, July 2018
- Neural Networks from Scratch, Infiniteconf 2017, July 2017
- The Brief on Developer Book Clubs, London Web Standards, January 2017
- Progressive Web Applications, Web Platform London, December 2016

Courses

- Data Analyst Track Dataguest.io, online, October 2017
- Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree Udacity, online, February 2017
- Web Development Immersive General Assembly, London, UK, March 2014

Education

Data Science MSc, Distinction 2018 - 2021

2008 - 2012

City, University of London, UK

Physics with Theoretical Physics MSci, First Class

Imperial College London, UK

- Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme (UROP) June - August 2011